so there's a question about uh the eight
precepts but in particularly their
precept against
entertainments like playing games
watching movies uh just distraction I suppose
movies uh just distraction I suppose
distracting yourself
and why why is that an issue you know
simple game kind of
just you're feeling under pressure
you're keeping the precepts and you just
want to relax yeah so it's an issue
because you're not free from suffering
yet that's why it's an
issue if you were to be free from
suffering then yes there are those
things that could be deemed neutral in
in in and of themselves like oh it's
just and that's why people would often
like trying to reason kind of divorced
from their situation and look at it on
its own it's like well it's not a big
deal and yeah fact it's not a big deal
but paid with your non-freedom from
suffering those things would then result
in um uh greed aversion delusion that
you're not free from INF festering
increasing if you were free from those
things then yes those neutral activities
even entertainment would
not would not cause that because you
would have removed it you would have you
would have basically um removed the UNH
wholesome roots that are still present
in you so that's why you need to
renounce those activities as well until
you're free from suffering until you
have
uprooted the cause of all problems so to
speak um then yeah if if you choose to
whatever for whatever reason and Eng
with something that might be deemed
entertainment externally well it won't
be an entertainment for you because the
nature of entertainment is the nature of
distraction distraction from the present
situation that is bothering that is
oppressing that you are not free from
internally but yeah if you just judge it
by the external activity on paper it's
always it's nothing to it because there
isn't anything to it but why is it being
done what is your intention behind it
then you realize oh yeah now there's a
whole world of difference
CU that's it seems to me it well it is
you feeling uh displeasure you're feeling
feeling uh displeasure you're feeling
Bolden and you want to get rid of that
it has to be exactly CU cuz those are
things for as long as you're not free
from suffering means those things are
still be going to be pressuring you I
don't know think about like you just I
don't know put a blanket over a grass
and it's just a blanket on the grass
what's the problem with it well what's
underneath the
blanket and it's like these these weeds
and roots they will now grow even
more but if you remove it expose it to
the Sun they'll dry up and die then put
all blankets you want on the ground but
not before you would have got rid of the
stuff that needs to be needs to be dealt
with again why would you as you said why
would you what's the reason for
distracting why would be the reason for
example watching a movie sometimes it
can even be just a habit for people even
if it's not necessarily like fully um
defined pressure to to distract myself
it's just careless habit just not even
think about it in general it's like an
escape an escape yeah yeah but again
like even an escape in and of itself
it's not a problem if there is nothing
you're trying to
escape right but you won't be in a
position to be not trying to escape
anything I
freed if you would not have stopped all
those activities beforehand because as I
said for as long as greed diversion
illusion are still there underlying your
experience those escapes would serve to
to to would provide food for those for
those UNH wholesome Roots would feed
them that's why they are UNH wholesome
but if say arant has uprooted all these
things from his from his um experience
as a whole then entertainment there is
nothing to feed so and then exactly how
much would then he enjoy it well that's
a question of
individual person I suppose but um
because the reason for enjoyment is
usually exactly that self forgetfulness
and and disappearance from the
current state of your of your kind of
emotional state feeling pressure boredom
all these things that could be there
simply have taking a break from yourself
basically that's what it translates
to that whole entertainment industry is
like one of the biggest Industries you
know cuz that's because everybody
everyone's suffering and it's like that
it's just such an easy way to to go to
to escape your reality it's built on
your suffering basically it's like yeah
because like if you if you and you
realize how much people would be
dependent on it because if you were to
just stop for example entertainment the
pressure would
increase that's it like if you're not
for as long as you're not stopping it it
might not seem like a big deal but then
if you choose to stop it just as an
experiment then you realize oh so I just
have to spend the entire day without
forgetting about myself through these
activities and you just oh that's the
unpleasant part just being with yourself
because why is it as I as I ask often
why is it just sitting with yourself
doing nothing why is that unpleasant why
is that um
kind of something that people would be
resisting by
default no just doing nothing not
distracting myself not trying to you know get rid of
myself not trying to you know get rid of
anything not trying
to and yet it's like it's the worst
thing you ask yourself these things and
you realize yeah yeah it's not even
unpleasant like it's not even like that
you that you really hate or something
it's just like by default you want to
look away from yourself
by default you want to be taken
elsewhere and that's a habit that then
fasters and proliferates and you become
more and more dependent on
that and as any other habit you can undo
it by not providing fuel for it so by
reducing the distraction and
entertainment and and giving it up you
are bringing yourself back to yourself
in a sense of like okay so now I'm with
myself and I don't need to make some
extra crazy determined effort to be
present in the moment with myself all I
need to do is not distract myself from
myself and I am present in the moment
with myself so mindfulness and awareness
will be there cuz you're not basically
hindering it with all these habitual
actions of of uh towards entertainment
and delusion and distraction